Altan Kurt

Software Developer

★ altankurt.dev 🗘 altankurt in altankurt • altankurt 💌 hello@altankurt.dev 🗘 Izmir, Turkey

Summary

My passion for software development is fueled by a commitment to creating innovative solutions and enhancing product development.

My career change journey, fueled by a deep passion for technology and a commitment to lifelong learning, has led to my specialization in React, Next. is and JavaScript, marking a significant evolution in my professional path.

Constantly experimenting with different technologies to broaden my skill set, I contribute significantly to both personal and open-source projects.

My past experiences have endowed me with a profound understanding of teamwork and the ability to successfully complete projects within deadlines. With a clear vision of evolving into a full-stack developer, I am steadfast in my commitment to continuous learning and self-improvement.

Tech Skills

TypeScript | JavaScript | React | Next.js | TailwindCSS | SASS | Git | REST API | Figma | Vite | HTML5 | CSS3

Projects

Wordigo 2

A platform where you can translate unfamiliar words while browsing the web with your browser, add them to your personal dictionary, and share them.

- Managed tasks and workflow within the team as Development Manager
- Developed the **product roadmap** by auditing **issues** to improve project efficiency.
- Developed reusable UI components and style templates.
- Implemented authentication and **OAuth2** structure using **Next.js**.
- Added multi-language support and implemented necessary SEO optimizations.

GitHub 🛮

altankurt.dev 🛮

My personal website, crafted with modern technologies, showcases my writings and professional works

- Built a website & blog platform with Next.js
- Developed reusable UI components
- Used **dynamic routing** for blog posts and **static** for the projects page
- Optimized for SEO and integrated Google Analytics for traffic insights
- Implemented a modern and responsive design with TailwindCSS
- Added theme switching for multi-theme feature

GitHub 🛮

Student Course Hub

It is a CRM platform developed to enable efficient management of courses and registered students.

- Built a platform using **React** & **Vite** for top-tier performance
- Implemented **REST API** for course management
- Adopted **React Router v6** for seamless SPA navigation
- Implemented **authentication** system into the application
- Developed reusable UI components

Email: mail@mail.com - Password: 12345

GitHub 🛮

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer

06/2022 - 09/2022

London, UK

Weblitious Ltd. (Contracted) 🗷

- Development interactive and responsive website using TailwindCSS and JavaScript.
- Participated in activities to optimize web performance.
- Worked closely with design and development teams to optimize UX/UI
- design.
- Collaborated on various web projects within a dynamic team

Operations Manager

KODA Network 🛮

03/2020 – 04/2022 Izmir, Turkey

• Analyzed and optimized business processes, implementing key projects like digital transformation and workflow improvements to boost efficiency.

- Restructured financial and HR frameworks, enhancing infrastructure with e-transformation and digital archiving.
- Led annual and quarterly financial planning, leveraging public incentives and cost strategies for enhanced efficiency.

Previous Experience 11/2012 – 02/2020
• Continuously improved organizational processes throughout roles ranging from Administrative and Izmir, Turkey

- Accounting Specialist to Operations Manager.
- Gained in-depth expertise in digital transformation and workflow optimization.
 Lod financial planning and resource allocation, bolstoring infractructure with a transformation.
- Led financial planning and resource allocation, bolstering infrastructure with e-transformation and digital archiving.
- Established strategic supplier relationships, optimizing the supply chain.
- Collaborated with public institutions and managed government incentives to ensure smooth operations.

Organizations

Açık Yazılım Ağı ☑ 02/2023 – present

Moderator

• In 2023, I voluntarily joined the Open Software Network to assist earthquake victims in Turkey, managed the "Disaster Map" project, and streamlined communication on the "Disaster Information" platform.

Frontendship ☑ 09/2022 – present

Community Manager

• In the frontend development community as a volunteer, I contributed to open-source projects, led event planning, promoted peer learning, and shared resources.

Education

A.D. Computer ProgrammingAnadolu University ☑ 2022 – present Eskisehir, Turkey

B.D. Business AdministrationAnadolu University ☑ 69/2012 – 07/2014
Eskisehir, Turkey

A.D. Accounting and Tax

Mugla Sitki Kocman University ☑ 09/2010 – 08/2012

Mugla, Turkey

Languages

Turkish (Native), English (Intermediate (B1, 1+))